Okay, so I promised I'd show you how
this is simplified. So if you recall on
this one, we had to set a timeout and
then inside of that timeout, we had to
set our next timeout. And then inside of
that timeout, we had to set our next
timeout and so on and so forth down the
line. And that was terrible. And that's
how you would do it with callback
functions to handle asynchronous code.
So if you needed to get data and then
you depended on that data for your next
function, you'd have to write your next
function inside of that first function
to get a second set of data and so on
and so forth until you nested into a
giant tree. With promises, it gave us
the ability to use dot then. Um, so we
could say uh wait 3 seconds, then wait 5
seconds, then wait 2 thou uh 2 seconds,
then wait 4 seconds, and so on and so
forth. But chaining the thens does look
a little different and can lead to some
results. So like if down here I wrote
console.log
hello world, this hello world would
probably run before this very first
console.log. log because this first
console.log won't run until 3 seconds
later. And so it's counterintuitive to
realize that because this is outside of
the then chain, it might run on its own
beforehand. So let's rewrite this with
async and await so that our code's a
little simpler to read. So to do that,
we need to write our async function. So
we'd say async um async, sorry, async
function
um and I'm going to call it run.
Sorry, my keyboard shortcuts are going
wild. I clicking some wrong keys. All
right, so I could say let's run this
function. Um, and I'm actually going to
paste it in because I don't want to type
this much.
Sorry, one second.
This code is the equivalent of the above
code.
So, we still have our function for a
waiting. Um, but here inside of our
asynchronous run function, we said wait
3 seconds, then log it. wait 5 seconds,
then log it. And this code just runs
line by line like you would expect. The
only difference is this line won't run
until this line is complete because we
used the await keyword inside of an
asynchronous function. Then once we were
done, we ran it. So those lines are the
equivalent
of those lines and those lines are the
equivalent of these lines. But if you
ask me, this code is the easiest to
read. So, these devs, no moment of
silence for them. They're really
spoiled. Um, we're really spoiled. But
this way allows us to write all of the
power of asynchronous code. Um, but to
write it as if it was synchronous